hey guys this looks like a fun one 2
squared of x equals square root of 2
plus X so for the very first step we can
do a domain restriction we know that
under these square roots we can't have a
negative number so that means that the X
has to be greater than or equal to zero
if x were less than zero this would be
undefined on the left hand side now we
could put a box around that so we're off
to a pretty good start we've already
gotten rid of all the negative numbers
next to get rid of both these square
root symbols let's Square both sides of
the equation on this right hand side the
square root and the square cancel
leaving us with Just 2 plus X on the
left hand side this Square distributes
to both terms 2 squared and the square
root of x squared 2 squared is equal to
4 the square root and the two cancel
each other out leaving us with just 4X
and we were able to do this step because
X is greater than or equal to zero next
we can subtract X from both sides 4X
minus one X is 3x these X's cancel
leaving us with just two we can divide
both sides by three and that leaves us
with x equal to two-thirds and that's
the answer to our question how exciting